



Professional Summary

Enthusiastic, self-starting, and dedicated software developer. Currently enrolled in an intensive Bootcamp at Coder Academy in Melbourne, building proficiency in front and backend programming languages and gaining experience in testing frameworks. Critical thinking and excellent problemsolving skills due to a background in business that helps to create MVPs that meet user and business requirements.



Address

Melbourne, VIC, 3000

Phone

047 383 7804

E-mail

vipul.seth022@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ in/vipul-seth-a06730184/

Git Hub

https://github.com/vipul022



Education

2020-03 -2021-01 Diploma, Information Technology

Coder Academy - Melbourne

Skills

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript

2019-07 -Current **ISTQB** Foundation Level Certification

ANZTB

React, React Testing Library, Jest

2004-03 -2007-02 **Bachelors of Business Administration**

D.A.V. College - Amritsar(India)

MongoDB, Express JS, NodeJS

1990-03 -2003-02

Holy Heart High School - Amritsar(India)

Ruby, Ruby on Rails

SQL, Postgres



Projects Done

Project Name: FarmerSmart

Description:

Website Link: https://secure-brook-35449.herokuapp.com/

 Git hub Link: https://github.com/vipul022/farmersmart

A two-sided marketplace app built on Ruby on

Git, Git hub, Command

Line

Visual Studio Code,

Postman

Tools - Figma, Lucid chart,

Rails framework as an assessment for term 2 at Coder Academy.

DB diagram

Project Name: Portfolio Website

Description:

- Website Link https://vipulseth.netlify.app/
- Git hub Link:

https://github.com/vipul022/vipul022-my-portfolio

 Portfolio website created using HTML5 and CSS as an assessment for term 1 at Coder Academy.

Project Name: Weather or Not

Description:

 Website Link: https://www.jasonstacy.com.au/src/assets/weather
or not/

Git hub Link:

https://github.com/vipul022/hackathon

- Weather App built on Vanilla JavaScript using weatherbit api
- Participated in the JavaScript remote hackathon and peer programmed using the git forking workflow.

Project Name: Express Chat

Description:

- Website Link: https://calm-crag-33201.herokuapp.com/
- Git hub Link: https://github.com/vipul022/chat-app
- Real time chat application built using express server, socket.io and MongoDB database
- Used express-handlebars for front end
- Participated in the Express remote hackathon and peer programmed using the git forking workflow.

Project Name: South of the River Potters Club

Description:

 Website Link: https://southoftheriverpottersclub.herokuapp.c
om/

- Git hub link: https://github.com/vipul022/sotrpc_client
- Website built in MERN stack for South of the River Potters Club as final assessment for term 3 at Coder Academy.



Work History

2016-12 -2020-02

Service Provider

UPS Pty Ltd, Melbourne, Victoria

- Completed on-time deliveries by choosing best and most efficient routes
- Conferred with dispatch to relay delays, receive route and adjust plans to meet daily targets
- Fostered positive working relationships with customers by responding to questions and concerns

2015-08 -2016-11

Service Provider

Limitless Couriers, Melbourne, Victoria

- Coordinated efficient routes for optimal delivery scheduling and maximum daily performance
- Worked for various companies (DHL, Fastway, Couriers Please, UPS)

2009-11 -2015-01

Proprietor

Veekay Textiles, Amritsar, India

- Grew textiles business from ground up, including developing business plans, managing accounts and obtaining initial investments
- Developed and managed relationships with vendors and suppliers
- Traveled to various states of India in order to expand the business

2005-08 -2008-10

Co-Owner

Bhagwati Enterprises, Amritsar, Punjab

 Developed key operational initiatives to drive and maintain substantial business growth

- Managed purchasing, sales, marketing, and customer account operations of family-owned cotton waste recycling factory
- Drove setting up of latest machinery to propel the business forward and adapt to market changes